

Sarah Yaa Amoah Abeka

Nutrionist & Food Scientist

🔀 sarahyaa2018@gmail.com 📞 +233559555194 💡 Tema/Ghana 🏲 Ghanaian

k https://www.sarahabeka.com/ in https://www.linkedin.com/in/sarah-abeka-bb7810246

Profile

Skilled Nutritionist and Food Scientist with proven academic and practical understanding of Micro-biology, Nutritional Physiology, Nutrients and their Metabolism, Food Analysis, Sensory Science, Nutrient Interrelationship and needs, and Thermal Processing to mention a few. I have strong sensory analytic and research experience. I respond positively to assignments, and enjoy participation in teamwork. My goal is to become a nutritionist.

Education

BSc. Biological Science (Nutrition and Food Science), University Of Ghana ☑	08.2018 - 09.2022 Accra, Ghana
Chemistry, Biology & Physics, Holy Child High School	05.2014 - 10.2018 Cape Coast, Ghana

Professional Experience

Sensory Analyst Trainee, Department of Nutrition and Food Science, University of Ghana 🛮

01.2022 - present | Legon/Accra, Ghana

Responsible for analyzing and characterizing food product

Nutrition Counselor (Internship), Tema General Hospital

06.2021 - 08.2021 | Tema, Ghana

- Obtain and analyze patients' dietary history
- · Asses patients' eating habit and pattern
- Counselling patients and advising them on the best and suitable nutritional practices
- Regular monitoring of patients' status

Regulatory Officer (National Service Personnel),

Accra, Ghana

Food and Drugs Authority ♂

- Assessed residents in a long term care (LTC) and skilled nursing setting for nutrition risk and applied medical nutrition therapies accordingly, such as intervention with oral supplements
- Collaborated with the dietary department to initiate new dysphagia standard IDDSI into practice
- Lead weekly meetings on a QAPI initiative for prevention of excessive weight loss
- Applied medical nutrition therapies to nutrition problems in the acute care setting
- Conducted inservices and audits for the dietary department to ensure food safety compliance

Skills

Sales	Inspection	Nutrition counseling	Research
Microsoft Excel	Microsoft Powerpoint	Minitab Statistical Data Analytics tool	
Languages			
Twi	• • • •	English	• • • •
Interests			
• Cooking	• Reading	Listening to music	

References

Dr. Fredrick vuvor, University Of Ghana fvuvor@ug.edu.gh, +233(244698344)

Dr. Maame Yaakwah Blay-Adjei, University Of Ghana mybadjei@ug.edu.gh, +233(545525974)

Dr. Bennett Atta Dzandu, Univrsity Of Ghana badzandu@uq.edu.gh, +233(0504714855)

Prof M. Steiner-Asiedu

tillysteiner@gmail.com, +233(0541260794

Dr. Angela Parry-Hanson, University Of Ghana aparry-hanson@ug.edu.gh, +233(0272715759)

Prof. Esther Sakyi-Dawson, University Of Ghana esakyid@ug.edu.gh, +233(244367242)

Dr. Hussein Mohammad, University Of Ghana hmohammed@ug.edu.gh, +233(0559369505)

Projects

Food Generator Tool 01.2023

I collaborated with Solomon Yaw Adeklo (a web developer) to develop and integrate a food generator web app onto my portfolio website. Find thousands of foods you can generate with my online tool! Note: The tool works more conviniently on a desktop computer.

Click here to generate your favourite food for https://www.sarahabeka.com/recipegenerator/

Academic research (Undergraduate), Exporing the gaps in

10.2022

sensory and consumer science education and industry practice

in selected food companies in Ghana -

I completed a research project in 2022 Exploring the gaps in sensory and consumer science education and industry practice in selected food companies in Ghana. This study aims to explore the knowledge gaps between what students are taught and how they apply this knowledge in industry. The study was done by administering a semi-structured questionnaire using one-on-one interviews and online surveys to students, lecturers, and staff of food companies.

Download full documentation with this link 👉 https://www.sarahabeka.com/Finalyearproject.pdf